Wow, that is fantastic. That is
extraordinary. Way to go, Elon. We
backed him.
>> How would you describe that company?
It's so many things.
>> How would I describe SpaceX? I think
SpaceX is the company that is going to
take us to Mars and all of the things
that come along with it. When Kennedy
said, "We're going to the moon."
>> We choose to go to the moon not because
they are easy, but because they are
hard,
>> we were first other than Elon. Elon put
the first 30 million of his own money in
Steve. um spent most of his nights and
weekends launching rockets. He was just
so obsessed. And I said, "Look, you're
so obsessed with rockets. Find us the
best rocket company." And he came back
about 3 weeks later. He said, "The best
rocket company is Elons. He needed it."
And the first couple of rockets after
the investment blew up on the launch pad
and we thought, "Oh boy, that was that
money went away pretty fast."
Today's guest is the legendary venture
capitalist Tim Draper. He was an early
investor in companies like Hotmail,
Skype, BU, Tesla, SpaceX, Coinbase,
Robin Hood, Twitch, and many, many more.
These are companies that went on to
reshape how the world communicates,
moves, and think about money. The
Drapers are also one of the most
legendary families in Silicon Valley
history. His grandfather helped build
modern VC before Silicon Valley became
what we know today. His father founded
Sutter Hill Ventures and helped shape
the culture of Senh Hill Road, earning
the reputation of the godfather of
Silicon Valley venture capitalist. And
today, the Drapers have become a four
generation venture capital family.
Tim, it's such an honor to have you on
the show. I've been a big fan.
>> Terrific. Well, it's been fun to have
fun to be on your show and happy to do
it again.
>> Oh, already? Well, I love that. I love
that. You know, I remember seeing you at
the Mara Lago Trump event and there was
a wall of people around you and I was
there thinking there's probably like a
98% chance that you you do not want
another random person speaking to you
right now.
But I did it anyway because if there was
like this 2% chance I had to take it and
here we are today,
>> you know.
>> Terrific. Well, I do like um I do like
people and that helps uh because I do
get um I get a lot of interest. Uh much
of it is because I'm a venture
capitalist and well known and I do early
stage investing and they um and a lot of
people have interesting ideas they want
to um run across me or um or real
business plans where they they want to
make those things happen. So, uh,
I, um, and I appreciate them. They come
from all over. I see my eyebrows once
again out of control. Um,
>> you have the most iconic eyebrows.
So, uh, I I find it good to go out and,
um, and see people because I learn a lot
from a lot of different people. And I
learn about what the future might hold.
And that u mostly because people like to
come to me and talk about the future and
what it's going to look like. Um, and
that was a great event. Uh, that that um
Mara Lago event on on Bitcoin. I thought
I thought it was a great event. Very
well put together
>> and really some extraordinary people. I
met Mike Tyson.
>> Yeah.
>> Who's a great philosopher.
>> Some people think boxer
or an actor. Um, and uh, yeah, I I
really enjoyed uh, I enjoyed a lot of
the speeches. I enjoyed the um, the
interactions I had. Um, and it's such a
beautiful location.
>> I would imagine you, you know, walk
around with a bunch of security and
you're like, you know, don't talk to me.
But you were so open to everybody
approaching you.
There was a lot of security going in.
>> I mean, yeah. Yeah.
>> President Trump was going to be
>> Yes. Yes. So, you were okay. You felt
safe.
>> I He was protecting himself from me. Um,
>> you're talking about people pitching you
the future and, you know, now Wall
Street and and literally everybody is
talking about SpaceX. You backed them
very early on.
>> Yeah, we were first.
>> Tell us.
>> Oh, you were first.
>> We were first. Other than Elon. Elon put
the first 30 million of his own money
in. Uh
>> what was the story like? What was the
first encounter?
>> Well, it's really credit to Steve
Jervson,
my partner at the time. Steve um spent
most of his nights and weekends
launching rockets. He was just so
obsessed. And I said, "Look, you're so
obsessed with rockets. Find us the best
rocket company." And he came back about
three weeks later, maybe it was a couple
months later, and he said, "The best
rocket company is Elons."
And I said, "Isn't he supposed to be
running Tesla?" And because we we had a
big investment in Tesla. And he said um
he said, "Yeah, but I think we should
hear him out." So uh when we talked to
Elon, we got this um
amazing
feeling from him um that his mission in
life was really to make us multilanetary
and there was um there was so much
passion tied to
uh getting us to Mars or whatever else
he wanted to do that I realized that
that was what he was really put on the
earth for and Tesla was sort of a means
to an end. And uh well, he also wanted
to save the plan, our planet here, but
he also wanted us to get off this planet
potentially.
And um yeah, so we backed him and that
was u boy that was an amazing
u
decision. I'm I'm thrilled we did and we
put a lot of money into it, too, cuz
hey, he needed it. And the first couple
of rockets after the investment blew up
on the launchpad and we thought, "Oh,
boy, that was
that money went away pretty fast."
Uh but then one of the Falcon uh ones um
lifted off and worked and
uh suddenly there were plenty of
contracts and he was off to the races.
So, um, way to go, Elon. And, you know,
he has that great way of saying, "Hey,
we're going to Mars." And when you get
a,
um, a big mission like that, uh, you
attract the best entrepreneurs in the
world. you you attract the best
engineers and scientists and everybody
wants to come join you because they want
to go to Mars or they they want to think
about that problem. That's a much better
problem than another SAS product or
whatever. So Elon really um
uh attracted some of the best talent and
that talent of course has come up with
some amazing things. Starlink.
Starlink
is pretty pretty frustrating. We have
fiber to the home here.
And uh my Starlink works better than my
fiber to the home.
Um
wow, what an amazing company. And on
your way to Mars, you're going to find
so many other things.
Uh,
and I don't know if space is the final
frontier, but it's the frontier of the
now.
>> So, in the SpaceX IPO mission statement,
he actually talked about, you know,
building this civilization beyond Earth
like you said, but the there is this
really real like hot debate on the
internet. It says once the company
becomes public now you know ordinary
people who might not have that vision
have to buy in through ETFs and stuff.
Do you think the public or you know
everyday people are ready for such a big
mission?
Well, to go I don't know if they're
ready to go to Mars, but I'm I certainly
I have plans myself to eventually go to
the moon.
>> Um
I think that they have uh I mean the
public I I think you underestimate
people. I think they have great
imaginations.
I think they're um
I think a lot of people are a little um
they live in a scared world. They don't
want to um they don't want to see change
because they've got to like I've got a
system working. I have a job and I get
food and shelter and clothing
>> and occasionally I get to go out to the
movies or whatever. I kind of like this.
So, if somebody comes and shakes them up
and says, "Hey, we're going to Mars,"
uh, it's one of two reactions. One is,
I I I don't want to go to Mars. I don't
want anybody to go to Mars. I don't
think anyone should. Whatever. And
that's one. And the other one is like,
wow, that is fantastic. That is
extraordinary. I can't wait to see what
happens here. And um and people who buy
shares of public stocks, I think, are
going to look and say, I want a piece of
that. I want a piece of that future,
whatever that is.
>> So, how would you describe that company
now?
It's so many things.
>> How would I describe SpaceX?
>> Mhm.
Um,
I think SpaceX is the company that is
going to take us to Mars and all of the
things that come along with it. It's a
little like when Kennedy said, "We're
going to the moon." feed. But I do say
that space can be explored and mastered
without feeding the fires of war,
without repeating the mistakes that man
has made in extending his rit around
this globe of ours. There is no strife,
no prejudice, no national conflict in
outer space as yet. Its hazards are
hostile to us all. Its conquest deserves
the best of all mankind and its
opportunity for peaceful cooperation may
never come again.
But why, some say the moon? Why choose
this as our goal? And they may well ask,
why climb the highest mountain? Why, 35
years ago, fly the Atlantic? Why does
Rice play Texas? We choose to go to the
moon. We choose to go to the moon.
We choose to go to the moon in this
decade and do the other things not
because they are easy but because they
are hard
>> and all sorts of new technologies came
from that.
I think it was like the transistor came
from that. Some amazing things came from
people saying solving a big problem like
that. So you you create a goal like hey
we got to all be able to live on Mars.
How are we going to do that? And then
you start thinking about well how do you
do it? You terraform it uh before you
get there? Do you how how can you get
there faster than six months? how can
you um so people start thinking in
really extraordinary ways and so I
actually think SpaceX is um you know the
company that's going to take us to Mars
but along the way is going to have
things like Starlink
um
and I guess also Twitter is now a part
of it and and X X.ai AI. Um,
actually I I use all the AI products and
X.AI is the one I go to for the truth.
Uh
>> Oh, I think
>> Oh, interesting. Yeah, because uh the
rest of them um are a little coddling
and they uh
not all of them, but but they some feel
like they're written by lawyers or
people who are very
>> politically correct or whatever
>> and or or some of them just want to make
me feel better.
>> Oh yeah. And sometimes sometimes I just
want the facts and that's where I go uh
to x.ai.
>> Do you think everybody should be an
entrepreneur? Because you push people to
think bigger.
>> Um I encourage them to fight. I
encourage them to do things and try
things and explore
and
uh fail and fail again until they
succeed. I encourage them to
um promote freedom and trust around the
world. I I encourage them to do things
that are
um where they're willing to take a
chance on something that might not work.
That is a much better way to live in my
mind. And it's also moves humanity
forward a lot faster.
uh then if you take away people's
freedoms, you overregulate and overt
tax.
If you tell everybody what to do, if
you're
the leaders of a group, you're telling
everybody what to do, then they live in
fear and they are afraid to take
chances. They're afraid to speak out and
they're afraid to think big. they're
afraid to think
imaginatively.
Um,
I mean, I felt that during the whole
COVID fiasco where people were telling
me what I was supposed to think and um
that that woke thing where it's like
you're not allowed to say things. Now,
part of the beauty of America and the
beauty of the Silicon Valley is that
people have the freedom of speech and
they can say whatever they want. And by
saying whatever you want, you can make
mistakes and get and then get admonished
for them. Um and you and that's good
because you that give and take makes you
better and stronger and um and more
sensitive person.
Um
remarkably it's sort of the has the
opposite effect. Freedom of speech makes
you more sensitive because you you were
able to try so so many more things. It
also makes you much more imaginative
and that imagination is really what
drives humanity forward and that's where
we we take these amazing anthropological
leaps. Uh and they're happening faster
and faster. So, you know, it was a long
way from when we had the industrial
revolution to where we had the
automobile.
And there was a long way from the
automobile to the computer,
but it was a pretty short way from the
computer to software and a really short
way from software to the internet and an
a really really short way from the
internet to Bitcoin and from Bitcoin to
artificial intelligence and from
artificial intelligence to whatever we
do next will also be a short time
horizon which means that each of these
anthropological leaps forward
uh is happening faster and faster and
that is very exciting. That means that
our lives will I mean if you look back
150 years
I mean there's no indoor plumbing.
There's no electricity. There's no no
cars, no computers, no Door Dash, no
AI, no Bitcoin, none of that. Um it was
people I think people were still trading
gold or maybe the promise of gold. Um
they were a long way from here and uh
and so if you go forward 150 years it's
going to be amazing. And you know how
you think oh you know it'd be nice to be
able to go back into all those wonderful
times. No way you'd want to go back 150
years, but going forward 150 years, that
will be amazing.
Um, God, think of all the amazing things
that people will come up with. And and
that's just our imaginations. We got the
imaginations of 8 billion people
and all of their kids and all of their
grandkids who are going to come out with
amazing new things. So, you know, going
to Mars will be like a a blink.
The the the
innovations that happen between now and
150 years from now are going to be
amazing. In fact, even 15 years from
now, we're seeing u people reversing
aging. We're seeing people with flying
cars. We're seeing I mean, all these
things are starting to happen.
And uh
yeah, I think it's going to be this is
going to be a really exciting uh 15
years. And then I think it'll keep
accelerating beyond that.
And the only resistance points to that
are um
insecure governments who create stupid
rules for people that they don't realize
that you know if you make a rule for 300
million people I mean like uh some new
regulation you think oh people should do
this you're forcing 300 million people
to do that. That is huge resistance.
That's friction to our economy. That's
friction to our progress.
So that's it's no surprise that the
freer the country,
the more progress they make. The
socialist countries always go flatline.
their economies go flatline because
they're they have weak leaders and they
tell everybody what to do and then
everybody just does that and that's
flatline no innovation.
Uh whereas the free countries and the
the capitalist countries grow at
extraordinary rates and the the
less regulation and the less
government friction um
mean that the country can grow that much
faster.
>> You talk about freedom a lot. Why is
that so important to you?
Well, I fund entrepreneurs.
Uh, if there were no freedom, there
would be no entrepreneurs.
Uh, they would be restricted. They would
not be creative. They would not think
outside of what we're all doing. They
would not try new things because in a
socialist restrictive environment, um,
they can't. They are punished
for thinking of anything outside of what
everybody thinks is normal.
And that um
that's why freedom matters.
>> Look at all these entrepreneurs and
builders. How do you identify who's the
real deal and who's just bsing?
>> It's usually pretty easy for me by now.
We have AI that does it, too.
We have sear and we have uh we have sear
and it can detect lies and uh we have
>> do you use those tools to you know help
you judge people or is it a
>> Oh, we use those tools really to help
improve those tools. Uh the tools aren't
as good as people yet.
We're just hoping they get as good. We
we use AI in about I don't know 15
different ways to improve our venture
business and some of the way we're using
it is just to train it so that we get it
gets better. Uh and some of it really
does help our business a lot. Um we also
use AI so you can submit your
uh business plan or your deck to uh
draper.vc VC, our site, and
uh we give you feedback and then you can
call uh my digital twin and you can talk
to that.
>> Wow.
>> And that AI gives you feedback on your
business. People have spent two and a
half hours with it and keep calling
back.
>> It's really interesting.
>> Can I know what type of people you're
looking for? because I'm sure there are
a lot of, you know, people watching this
and they're like, you know what, this is
interesting and they want to know if
they are the type of people you're
looking for.
>> Yeah. Draper University is what we call
a people accelerator. Uh it uh takes in
somewhat ordinary people with great
passion and turns them into
entrepreneurs.
uh in kind of an odd way. We have
survival training and we have a
three-day hackathon and we have a by the
end and we do business modeling and we
do at the end we do a
demo day with a bunch of uh venture
capitalists.
Uh
but we um we throw a lot at the
entrepreneur and we challenge them
um somewhat intellectually but mostly
it's um emotionally,
physically we challenge them.
>> Oh wow.
>> And spiritually we enlighten them. Uh so
we put a lot of things into that program
and it ends up um creating a lot of
great entrepreneurs. So it's it's been a
huge success. I think 7,000 people have
gone through hero training. About 24,000
people have gone through Draper
University in one form or another, but
7,000 have had hero training. They've
started about 3,500 companies and about
five are already unicorns. We're only 15
years old and five have become unicorns
and uh
and then about 25 are worth more than
$100 million
and the people who go have come from 104
different countries. So we are very
international.
>> Do you think that young would have
passed the university?
>> I would have loved it.
It's only five weeks. It's not like
wasting four years of your life.
>> It's only five weeks.
>> You used the word waste.
>> Yeah, I don't think it was a waste when
I went, but
boy, I think a lot of the university
system um needs major overhaul
and and it would be a waste
academically. I think you get a lot more
out of AI than you would out of a
university today. Um, socially, I think
you'd be good. It would be very good to
go to a
university.
>> Family education is pro probably one of
the most fundamental thing in a human
being and your family is one of the most
legendary VC families in history. You
know, your your dad is being called the
godfather of VC in Silicon Valley and I
was watching one of your father Stanford
talk recently and you know my favorite
part was he him talking about you and he
said you got hit by cars three different
times riding your bike smashed through
windshield at Stanford and drank snake
oil from a street vendor in Hong Kong.
And you know,
>> it was Taiwan.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, Snake Alley. Snake.
>> Oh, man.
>> Man,
how would you describe, you know, your
personality and the characteristics that
are most important to you?
>> Well, first, dad is awesome. He's 98.
>> Yeah.
>> He's the nicest guy in the world. uh
he's he's forgetting a lot of things,
but his processor works like a charm.
And so if I have a really complex
problem, I'll bring it to him
>> and he'll give me a creative solution
that I had never thought of.
>> Um I love my family. My family's
fantastic. I didn't really push for any
of them to become venture capitalists,
but I think they saw me having fun. So
they see it as a really uh
fun and interesting and exciting for us.
Well, you need to pay attention to your
family. You need to uh make sure that
they're that everybody's doing well and
that they're moving in the right
direction and um or their direction,
helping them with their direction,
whatever that may end up being.
Um,
and family should be fun.
>> They should be um
>> they should be entertaining for
everybody and it's so that people want
to be attached to them.
>> I think that, you know, that's probably
something that doesn't get talked about
much. Well, something that gets talked
about is family wealth usually doesn't
last past three generations, but the
Drapers are now a successful four
generation uh family. What are some
values or what do people need to know
about this success? I think the people
the reason that um families
um
falter after a few generations is that
they they spend too much of their time
thinking about preserving their wealth
or something.
You know, money is just a vehicle. It's
something that you can um use to
accomplish
great things. And I think it's actually
healthy for various families to um to
move up and down the food chain. I don't
think it's uh I I think it's good. I
mean, that's the American way, right?
You want everybody to be able to uh make
a living and
and then you want them to be able to
um build great wealth, which is great.
But the way you do it is you provide a
really great service to someone or to a
a you delight customers somehow and that
is how you provide a great service and
that's how you make money and then if
you make money then you can use that
money to grow that service and spread it
around the world or you can use that
money to assist other people in create
in delighting other customers.
Um,
yeah, I I I do go around I speak to
occasionally these
>> um family office conferences where
they're
>> getting together and they all talk about
wealth preservation and I think, "Oh
god, you guys are nuts."
>> First of all, it ruins the lives of the
grandchildren if they're all they're
worried about is preserving. It's like,
"Oh, I can't change anything. It's got
to stay the way it is." No, you've got
to have you gotta have the family feel
like they can do what they want.
>> And you were the first venture
capitalist to buy Bitcoin at four around
$4 and you lost it to Mount Gaus. You
bought it back through Silk Road auction
at around 600 something.
>> Yes. But then you
>> 632 and then it went down to 180
shortly.
>> And I bought the war at 180 actually.
>> I I would assume most people would have
been very discouraged or destroyed by
this sequence, but you believe in
Bitcoin. Where did that conviction come
from?
Well, I I actually think that technology
usually um sees the light of day and
better technology improves people's
lives and and in the case of a of a new
currency
um every time there was a new currency
uh it it became a a major wealth driver
for humanity.
uh when we went from shells to gold,
when we went from gold to the promise of
gold, when we went from the promise of
gold to the promise of a government,
uh when credit was created, all these
things
uh lifted
the world economy in a in a big way. And
one of the things I noticed was that
where in the US Bitcoin wasn't really
people weren't really paying much
attention,
uh, in in places like Africa and
Southeast Asia, they were paying a lot
of attention. Uh, and in places where
there was a a not a con very little
confidence in a currency, they were
paying a lot of attention.
Um, now we all know that Bitcoin is
better, faster, cheaper than the dollar.
It's it um is more frictionless. It's
more transparent, keeps perfect records.
Uh, it's open. Uh,
it's global.
U,
and it's not tied to some governmental
force.
And so ultimately it's better, cheaper,
faster. It is a better technology. So
ultimately it will see it see it will
see the light and that's what I had in
mind while I was um while I was making
those purchases. I I saw that it not
only was it better, faster, cheaper, but
it was also
uh allowing people who were unbanked to
be a part of the world economy
and uh and that you know that also
increases uh the growth of the global
wealth.
I there were so many reasons and so I um
yeah so Bitcoin really
>> um and now it's on its way now it's
it's kind of accepted pretty much
everywhere. Retailers haven't quite
gotten there yet but they will. And when
they realize that they can make more
money if they just accept Bitcoin. I
would like you to maybe, you know,
challenge my idea a little bit because I
started this channel making videos and,
you know, breaking barriers and access
for myself and for my audience because,
you know, there's always this fear of
not belonging to the big rooms or not
being able to access the most
influential people like yourself. And
during this, you know, 4 and 1/2 years,
I grew into
something that could, you know, sit down
with people like you. And I'm very lucky
to have the opportunity. But I think I
constantly have this feeling of, you
know, this journey is still very early
for me, but
>> good. Keep that feeling.
>> Exactly. But there is
>> Keep that feeling. It's always early.
There always more. There are other
mountains to climb.
Just keep
>> keep thinking. I got to keep trying,
pushing,
excelling, asking.
>> I'm just wondering like am I thinking
too small? Like do I also have these
limiting beliefs for this channel or
what it could have become or is it where
am I heading to?
>> I It's You're on your own journey. I
think you're gonna enjoy it. Um you I if
you really work hard, you're gonna look
back when you're my age and you're gonna
say, "Wow,
that was something."
If this is your mission,
I think you should just enjoy your
mission and do do work as hard as you
can. Try always be a little
uncomfortable. Do stuff that makes you a
little uncomfortable. If you keep doing
that and always do the hardest thing
first, you're going to feel much better.
You're going to feel great when you're
my age.
>> I want to end this conversation with PS.
We love you.
>> I hope you know what I'm referring to.
>> That's That's the way hot every Hotmail
message was supposed to have that PS. I
love you on the
>> Terrific. Well, thank you so much,
Bonnie. It's fun to be on your show.